<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Troop 463 Sunnyvale</title>
    <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Troop 463 Sunnyvale</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Troop 463 Sunnyvale. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://troop463sunnyvale.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Info for Parents</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/resources/info-for-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/resources/info-for-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scoutbook&#34;&gt;Scoutbook&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The troop uses Scoutbook to manage our calendar and track advancement. It&amp;rsquo;s critical that all scouts are able to login to scoutbook and are doing so to update their requirements. This is achieved by using the same login as for &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.scouting.org&#34;&gt;https://my.scouting.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow this URL for Scoutbook: &lt;a href=&#34;https://scoutbook.scouting.org/&#34;&gt;https://scoutbook.scouting.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will help parents understand Scoutbook if they run into any issues with the website.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.scoutbook.scouting.org/knowledge-base/scoutbook-tutorial-for-parents/&#34;&gt;https://help.scoutbook.scouting.org/knowledge-base/scoutbook-tutorial-for-parents/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;calendar&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone who wishes to subscribe to the troop calendar can import using the link below. For instructions, please see the Scoutbook tutorial above.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://api.scouting.org/advancements/events/calendar/52288&#34;&gt;https://api.scouting.org/advancements/events/calendar/52288&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Troop 463, we believe the purpose of Boy Scouts is threefold: to have fun, to learn skills, but most importantly, to become a better person through strong character development. Our adults and senior scouts emphasize that Scouting is not just about becoming an Eagle quickly but instead to develop real life skills in the process. Working through the Trail to Eagle is about building character not just putting forth a minimal effort. We encourage our scouts to always strive to put in their best effort and to develop pride in their accomplishments, whether that is in mastering a knot or leading their patrol in advancement and troop spirit. In the words of our Scoutmaster, &amp;ldquo;the rank badge is just a piece of cloth, it is the work required to achieve it that counts&amp;rdquo;. We feel proud to say that our Eagle Scouts truly represent what achieving the Rank of Eagle encompasses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Registered Adult</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/resources/becoming-registered-adult/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/resources/becoming-registered-adult/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following information is also available as a flyer: &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.io/g/BSATroop463/files/Adult%20Registration%20Steps.pdf&#34;&gt;https://groups.io/g/BSATroop463/files/Adult%20Registration%20Steps.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Youth Protection Training (YPT)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LiveScan Fingerprinting and California Mandated Reporter Training&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Register with the troop (can be done online) and select a non-SM/ASM volunteer position. Committee Member is a good starter. We do have other positions but you can be reappointed later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be approved by the Committee Chair, Gunjan Gupta&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be approved by SVMBC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn in 7 copies of your BSA health forms A and B and health insurance card attached to each (all double sided) to Lusie Apriliana, medical forms coordinator, ASAP.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do the online training for your position (can be done after joining).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typical turnaround time can take a few days to about 2 weeks for Council to approve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meetings</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each month, the leadership of Troop 463 gathers for the Patrol Leaders&amp;rsquo; Council to plan, among other things, the next month&amp;rsquo;s meetings, and any major outing that are coming up. Troop 463 has regular meetings during the school calendar months. Aug ? June. We meet Tuesday evenings from 7:30 to 9:00, with a pre-meeting and post-meeting for the leadership only. Therefore, we can incorporate a wide variety of activities within the 90 minutes, while still having an organized structure. During the off months, we may be off enjoying summer camp, or either on or prepping for a High Adventure trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many troops have New Scout Patrols, placing all the new scouts into a single patrol with an older scout as their guide. We have discovered that the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; way of structuring the patrols works better for all the scouts. When new scouts join us they are placed into the existing patrols (along with a couple of their buddies from cub scouts). This provides the young scouts with role models and provides the older scouts with the opportunity to teach and guide the new scouts. It also helps to ensure that tasks get done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Advanture</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/high-advanture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/high-advanture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Troop 463&amp;rsquo;s high adventure program provides the experienced Scouts an extra benefit that goes beyond our regular events and outings. While the main troop&amp;rsquo;s outings are a lot of fun, they must be structured for all of the Scouts. However, since the High Adventure group is composed of the older, more experienced Scouts, we can go on almost any adventure imaginable. To participate in the High Adventure group, the scout has to attain the rank of 1st Class before the trip and be willing to try new things that may challenge their comfort zone!! like having a fear of heights!! But still participating in a High Rope Challenge Course. Being First Class, allows the High Adventure group to go on more adventurous and more fun outings since everyone has the basic skills of scouting. Occasionally, activities we choose will also have age restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joining</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/joining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/joining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interested in joining Troop 463? These are the steps that each scout family needs to complete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;regular-tuesday-meetings&#34;&gt;Regular Tuesday Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We highly recommend joining one of the regular Tuesday meetings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.app.goo.gl/nvNatZVCjDN1ECBp7&#34;&gt;Sunnyvale United Methodist Church&lt;/a&gt;, 535 Old San Francisco Rd, Sunnyvale, CA 94086.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:troop463info@gmail.com&#34;&gt;troop463info@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please confirm ahead of time; there are weeks we don’t meet at church.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-prospect-info-nights&#34;&gt;New Prospect Info Nights&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year our troop also hosts special Info Nights for 5th grade Cub Scouts (aka AOLs).  Please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:troop463info@gmail.com&#34;&gt;troop463info@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; for the next available info night.  Come to an Info Night to learn more about Troop 463, our philosophy, and see if we may be a good fit for your family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the year 1968 Boy Scout Troop 463 was born.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A retired reverend, Daniel Lindstrom and a group of parents who wanted to create positive activities for the youth in our area helped form Troop 463. From 1969 to 1972 Chuck McRery served as our second scoutmaster. The person who sewed the first batch of neckerchiefs was Mrs. Marilou Prasek. We are proud that this original design is still worn by our scouts today. During the early years of our troops origin our Whadachoo cheer was created. Our current Scoutmaster, Brian Davis has been the ScoutMaster since 2017 and brings his passion of the outdoors and his desire to see all the scouts achieve the highest of standards in the scouting program.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Success</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/about/success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the 50+ years Troop 463 has had involved parents and excellent fund raising. Although Boy Scouts is a Boy Lead? program, a troop can not be successful without the full involvement from the parents, committed other adults, good fundraising and of course eager participation from the scouts themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fundraising&#34;&gt;FUNDRAISING&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our Troop does not sell Popcorn to earn funds (although we may do this to support the High Adventure program or for individual scouts to earn money towards their scout activities). We have two major events that cover all our troop expenses. Hands on the Arts (May) and Art and Wine (1st weekend of June).&#xA;Hands on the Art is a Saturday event. Our scouts sell ice cream and water. Working this event helps promote our troop and gets our scouts out into the community. Adults are essential to assist with the set up and sales support. Shift are usually only a couple hours and a lot of fun! Earnings at this event are very contingent on good weather.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 February: Joshua Tree</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2025-02-joshua-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2025-02-joshua-tree/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 January: Angel Island Backpacking</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2025-01-angel-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2025-01-angel-island/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 December: San Francisco Hostel Outing</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-12-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-12-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Itinerary:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hostel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lombard Street&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fortune Cookie Factory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cable Car Museum&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sue Bierman Park for lunch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coit tower&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ghiradelli Square&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hostel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://troop463sunnyvale.smugmug.com/Galleries-By-Year/2024/2024-December-SF-Hostel-Outing&#34;&gt;https://troop463sunnyvale.smugmug.com/Galleries-By-Year/2024/2024-December-SF-Hostel-Outing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 November: Tomales Bay Kayak Camping</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-11-tomales-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-11-tomales-bay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 1:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Head to Heart&amp;rsquo;s Desire Beach&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rent kayaks from Blue Water Kayaking&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paddle to the Marshall Beach Group Boat-Only campsite&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lunch, Setup Tent, Activity etc, spend the night at campsite&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Day 2:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paddle back to Heart&amp;rsquo;s Desire Beach&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Return kayaks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lunch?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Head home&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://troop463sunnyvale.smugmug.com/Galleries-By-Year/2024/2024-November-Tomales-Bay-Kayak-Camping&#34;&gt;https://troop463sunnyvale.smugmug.com/Galleries-By-Year/2024/2024-November-Tomales-Bay-Kayak-Camping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 October: Coyote Lake Webelos</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-10-coyote-lake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-10-coyote-lake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Photos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://troop463sunnyvale.smugmug.com/Galleries-By-Year/2024/2024-October-Coyote-Lake-Webelos&#34;&gt;https://troop463sunnyvale.smugmug.com/Galleries-By-Year/2024/2024-October-Coyote-Lake-Webelos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 September: Point Reyes Backpacking</title>
      <link>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-09-point-reyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://troop463sunnyvale.com/outings/2024-09-point-reyes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 1:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arrive at trailhead, Unload all gear, drivers with cars go down to Limantour Beach Parking, (eat dinner)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drivers come back in one car, park at trailhead&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start hiking to sky camp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup camp and go to sleep&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Day 2:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wakeup, breakfast&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pack up camp, start hiking to Coast camp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set bags down, walk down to Secret beach&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arrive back at camp for dinner&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Night game and campfire&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quiet time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Day 3:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
